A Finding Aid to the Fendrick Gallery Records, 1952-2001, in the Archives of American Art AAA.fendgall
Archives of American Art
- Artists Files, 1962-2001, undated; Series 1; (Box 1-42, OV 108-110; 41.5 linear ft.)
  - Kerne, Barbara, 1984-1989, undated (Box 26)
  - Kimball, Wayne, 1990, undated (Box 26)
  - King, Erika, 1979, 1983-1987, undated (Box 26)
  - King, Marcia, 1988-1989, undated (Box 26)
  - Kirschen-Cole, Stephanie, 1979-1992, undated; (2 folders) (Box 26)
  - Klaidman, Kitty, 1980-1989, 1993, 2000, undated (Box 26)
  - Knapp, Stephen, 1991-1993, undated (Box 26)
  - Knippers, Edward, 1985-1988, undated (Box 26)
  - Kosianski, Leonard, 1979, 1984-2001, undated (Box 26)
  - Kotler, Martin, 1984-1991, undated; (4 folders) (Box 26)
  - Kozmon, George, 1985-1990, undated (Box 27)
  - Kranking, Margaret, 1990, 1993, undated (Box 27)
  - Kray, Gordon, 1984-1988, undated (Box 27)
  - Krawczyk, Donald, 1989, undated (Box 27)
  - Krebs, Rockne, 1971-1981, undated (Box 27)
  - Kulicke, Robert, 1978, 1986-1992, undated (Box 27)
  - K, Miscellaneous, 1970, 1976-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - Lalanne, Claude & François (Box 27)
    - Accounts, 1983-1993, undated; (3 folders) (Box 27)
    - Architectural Blueprint/Horizon Magazine, 1984 (Box 27)
    - City of New Orleans/1984 Louisiana World Expo. (See also OV 109), 1983-1990, undated (Box 27)
    - Construction, 1982-1984, undated (Box 27)
    - Contracts, 1982-1986, undated (Box 27)
    - Dallas/Miami, 1983-1984, undated (Box 27)
    - Drawings, Correspondence, Publicity Materials, 1982-1987, undated (Box 27)
    - Drawings/Photocopies, 1983-1984, undated (Box 27)
    - Drawings & Photographs (See also OV 109), 1979-1987, undated (Box 27)
    - House & Garden Magazine/Folder-Lalanne Publicity, 1988. undated (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous Material, 1983-1992; (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - 1984 Louisiana International Water Sculpture Competition Photos (See also OV 109), 1983-1986, undated (Box 28)
    - Publicity/Drawings, 1979-1986, undated (Box 28)
  - Lanu, Olavi, 1984, undated (Box 28)
  - Lanyon, Ellen, 1972-1983, 2000, undated; (2 folders) (Box 28)
  - Lehman, Wendy, 1988-1990, undated (Box 28)
  - Levi, Paul, undated (Box 28)
  - Liberman, Alexander, 1971-1981, undated (Box 28)
  - Lichtenstein, Roy, undated (Box 28)
  - Ligare, David, 1989, undated (Box 28)
  - Lisiecki, Denise, 1987-1990, undated (Box 28)
  - Littleton, Harvey, 1979-1982, undated (Box 28)
  - Loeser, Thomas, 1989, undated (Box 28)
  - Lorber, Stephen, 1991-1992, undated (Box 28)
  - L, Miscellaneous, 1979-1990, undated (Box 28)
  - Madlener, Jorg, 1988-1989,undated (Box 28)
  - Madsen, Loren, 1978-1986, undated; (2 folders) (Box 28)
  - Maloof, Sam, 1983, 1985 (Box 28)
  - Mapelli, Elizabeth, 1983, 1989, undated (Box 28)
  - Maresca, Joseph, 1986, 1990-1991, undated (Box 28)
  - Mason, George, 1978-1981, undated (Box 28)
  - Matson, Karl, 1990 (Box 28)
  - McCartney, Scott, 1990, undated (Box 28)
  - McGowin, Ed, 1971-1983, 1990, 2000, undated; (4 folders) (Box 28)
  - McWhorter, William, 1986-1989, undated (Box 29)
  - Meadmore, Clement, 1971-1973, 1983, 1988-1997, undated; (2 folders) (Box 29)
  - Messer, Sam, 1983, 1986, undated (Box 29)
  - Meyer, Howard, 1983, undated (Box 29)
  - Minter, Marilyn, 1982, 1987-1990, undated (Box 29)
  - Moore, Arthur Cotton (Box 29)
    - General, 1989-1992, undated; (5 folders) (Box 29)
    - Photographs, circa 1990 (Box 29)
  - Moore, Diana, 1987-1993, undated (Box 29)
  - Morera, Alberico, 1963-1966, undated (Box 29)
  - Moroles, Jesus Bautista, 1986-1990, undated (Box 29)
  - Morris, Robert Lee, 1977-1984, 1999, undated; (2 folders) (Box 29)
  - Motherwell, Robert, 1969-1991, undated; (5 folders) (Box 30)
  - Mouton, Grover E., 1981-1996, undated (Box 30)
  - M, Miscellaneous, 1966-2000, undated; (4 folders) (Box 30)
  - Neel, Alice, 1976-1998, undated (Box 30)
  - Neijna, Barbara, 1977-1982, undated (Box 30)
  - Nelson, Joan, 1989 (Box 30)
  - Nesbitt, Lowell, 1973-1979, undated (Box 30)
  - Nevelson, Louise, 1971-1988, undated; (2 folders) (Box 30)
  - Nevelson, Louise, 1971-1988, undated; (2 folders) (Box 31)
  - Nice, Don, 1982-1990, undated (Box 31)
  - Noland, Kenneth, 1968-1988, undated (Box 31)
  - N, Miscellaneous, 1969-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 31)
  - O'Kane, Tim, 1983-1991, undated (Box 31)
  - Oldenburg, Claes, 1969-1977, undated (Box 31)
  - Ottornes, Tom, 1991, undated (Box 31)
  - O, Miscellaneous, 1967-1992, undated (Box 31)
  - Paley, Albert (See Series 2, Albert Paley) (Box 31)
  - Parish, Ray, 1987-1989, undated (Box 31)
  - Patten, Sherry, 1986-1989, undated (Box 31)
  - Patti, Tom, 1976-1988, undated; (4 folders) (Box 31)
  - Pearlstein, Philip, 1972-1989, undated; (2 folders) (Box 31)
  - Pernotto, James, 1978-1990, undated; (4 folders) (Box 32)
  - Phillips, Matt, 1971-1976, undated; (2 folders) (Box 32)
  - Phillips, Stephen John, 1986-1991, undated; (4 folders) (Box 32)
  - Piccillo, Joseph, 1978-1995, undated; (5 folders) (Box 32)
  - Picek, Louis, 1977-1983, undated (Box 32)
  - Picek, Louis, 1977-1983, undated; (2 folders) (Box 33)
  - Pierobon, Peter, 1985-1990, undated (Box 33)
  - Piet, John, 1979-1982, undated (Box 33)
  - Plattner, Phyllis, 1985-1991, undated; (3 folders) (Box 33)
  - Poirier, Anne and Patrick, 1986-1989, undated (Box 33)
  - Polanski, Lois, 1982-1991, undated (Box 33)
  - Pomodoro, Arnaldo, 1986-1988, undated (Box 33)
  - Ponce de Leon, Michael, 1962-1969, undated (Box 33)
  - Pond, Clayton, 1967-1991, undated; (4 folders) (Box 33)
  - P, Miscellaneous, 1964-1994, undated; (3 folders) (Box 33)
  - P, Miscellaneous, 1964-1994, undated; (2 folders) (Box 34)
  - Q, Miscellaneous, 1971, 1981 (Box 34)
  - Raffael Joseph, 1970-1998, undated; (7 folders) (Box 34)
  - Raimondi, John, 1972-1986, undated (Box 34)
  - Rauschenberg, Robert, 1967-2000, undated; (4 folders) (Box 34)
  - Read, Marcus Lora, 1990, undated (Box 35)
  - Reed, Paul, 1967-1984, undated (Box 35)
  - Reiman, William P., 1987 (Box 35)
  - Rheingold, Louis, 1973-1974, undated (Box 35)
  - Rhoades, George, 1984-1989, undated (Box 35)
  - Rickey, George, 1982-1999, undated; (3 folders) (Box 35)
  - Robin, Stephen, 1990-1997, undated (Box 35)
  - Robinson, Charlotte, 1980-1990, undated (Box 35)
  - Rogers, Terry, 1986-1990, undated (Box 35)
  - Rosas, Mel, 1982-1990, undated (Box 35)
  - Rose, Robin, 1977-1990, undated (4 folders) (Box 35)
  - Rosenquist, James, 1978, undated (Box 35)
  - Ross, Sheba, 1990, undated (Box 35)
  - Ross, Wendy, 1966-1990, undated (Box 35)
  - Ruppert, John, 1986-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 35)
  - Ruscha, Edward, circa 1970-1990, undated (Box 35)
  - R, Miscellaneous, 1970-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 35)
  - R, Miscellaneous, 1970-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 36)
  - Saari, Peter, 1979-2001, undated; (2 folders) (Box 36)
  - Samaras, Lucas, 1990, undated (Box 36)
  - São (Maria da Conceição), 1981-1998, undated (5 folders) (See also OV 110) (Box 36)
  - Sarkisian, Paul, 1969-1989, undated; (2 folders) (Box 36)
  - Sasso, Paul, 1989-1991, undated (Box 36)
  - Scholder, Fritz, undated (Box 36)
  - Shaffer, Mary, 1980-1991, undated (Box 36)
  - Shahn, Ben, 1967-1985, undated (Box 36)
  - Shaw, Richard, 1978-1987 (Box 36)
  - Sheer, Martha, 1989-1990 (Box 36)
  - Sinclair, Daniel, 1989-1993, undated (Box 37)
  - Singletary, Robert, 1970-1985, undated; (3 folders) (Box 37)
  - Slonem, Hunt, 1985-1990, undated (Box 37)
  - Smith, Clarice, 1982-1990, undated; (3 folders) (Box 37)
  - Smith, Jeffrey, 1990 (Box 37)
  - Smythe, David, 1989-1991, undated (Box 37)
  - Sonfist, Alan, 1978-1985, undated (Box 37)
  - Soppeland, Mark, 1978-1988, undated (Box 37)
  - Sorman, Steve, 1970-1990, undated; (2 folders) (Box 37)
  - Speaker, Michael, 1979-1983, undated (Box 37)
  - Spector, Buzz, 1987-1990, undated (Box 37)
  - Speziale, Gary, 1989, undated (Box 37)
  - Stackhouse, Robert, 1990 (Box 37)
  - Stanger, Jay, 1989, undated (Box 37)
  - Stark, Larry, 1969-1972, undated (Box 37)
  - Starn, Mark and Doug, 1988, undated (See also: OV 110) (Box 37)
  - Stayman, Wendy, 1985-1986, undated (Box 37)
  - Stefancic, Zarko, 1979-1989, undated (Box 37)
  - Steinback, David, 1987, undated (Box 37)
  - Steiner, Peter, 1984-1988, undated (Box 37)
  - Stella, Frank, 1971-1989, undated (Box 37)
  - Stevenson, Brockie, 1977-1992, undated; (5 folders) (Box 38)
  - Stewart, Bill, 1976-1999, undated (Box 38)
  - Stovall, Lou, 1985-1989, undated (Box 38)
  - Summer, Carol, 1962-2001, undated; (6 folders) (Box 38)
  - Suris, James, 1981-1986, undated (Box 38)
  - Suworoff, William, 1977-2000, undated; (3 folders) (Box 38)
  - Suworoff, William, 1977-2000, undated; (4 folders) (Box 39)
  - S, Miscellaneous, 1984-2001, undated; (4 folders) (Box 39)
  - Tenneson, Joyce, 1984-2001, undated; (6 folders) (Box 39)
  - Toral, Mario, 1977-1978, undated (Box 39)
  - Tsai, 1970-1984, undated (Box 39)
  - T, Miscellaneous, 1989-2001, undated; (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - Uravitch, Andrea, 1975, undated (Box 40)
  - U, Miscellaneous, 1975-1982, undated (Box 40)
  - Valentine, De Wain, 1985-1990, undated (Box 40)
  - Valerio, James, 1979-2001, undated (Box 40)
  - Volonakis, Michael, 1987-1992, undated (Box 40)
  - V, Miscellaneous, 1978-1998, undated (Box 40)
  - Wade, Bob, 1974-1990, undated (Box 40)
  - Warhol, Andy, 1980, undated (Box 40)
  - Watson, Genna, 1977-1988, undated; (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - Way, Andrea, 1979-1998, undated; (3 folders) (Box 40)
  - Weber, Idelle, 1980-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - Weinberg, Steven, 1983-1984, undated (Box 40)
  - Wasselman, Tom, 1970-1973, undated (Box 40)
  - White, Joe, undated (Box 40)
  - White, Walter, 1980-1994, undated; (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - White, Walter, 1980-1994, undated; (4 folders) (Box 41)
  - Wiley, William, 1972 (Box 41)
  - Wilson, Donald Roller, 1977-1996, undated; (5 folders) (Box 41)
  - Witt, Nancy, 1982-1985m undated (Box 41)
  - Woodward, William, 1976-2000, undated; (7 folders; See also OV 110) (Box 41)
  - Wright, Frank, 1986-1990, undated (Box 42)
  - W, Miscellaneous, 1981-1996, undated (Box 42)
  - Yamaguchi, Yoriko, 1984-1990, undated (Box 42)
  - Yarmolinski, Sirpa, 1974-1990, undated; (2 folders) (Box 42)
  - Yes, Phyllis, 1990 (Box 42)
  - Youngerman, Jack, 1972-1973 (Box 42)
  - X, Y, Z, Miscellaneous, 1968-1991, undated (Box 42)
  - Oversized Material for Sam Gilliam, 1991-1996, undated (Box OV 108)
  - Oversized Materials for Claude & François Lalanne, 1982-1984, undated (Box OV 109)
  - Oversized Materials for Miscellaneous Artists (Box OV 110)
    - São (Maria da Conceição), 1980, undated (Box OV 110)
    - Starn, Mark & Doug, 1987 (Box OV 110)
    - Woodward, William, undated (Box OV 110)
- Albert Paley, 1970-2001, undated; Series 2; (Box 42-54, 107, OV 111-113, OV 117-118; 14.5 linear ft.)
  Files documenting the relationship between Albert Paley and the Fendrick Gallery including correspondence, scattered design drawings, exhibition and commission material, photographs, slides, audio-visual materials, notes, publicity and other printed matter. Included in these files is the draft of an unpublished manuscript about Paley, written by Daniel Fendrick. Arrangement of the series is by type of material. Documents within the individual folders are arranged chronologically by year. Researchers should also consult Series 3, Commissions for Albert Paley's commission projects managed by the gallery.
  - Accounts (Box 42)
    - General, 1981-1990, undated; (3 folders) (Box 42)
    - Albert Paley Photographs, 1982-1985 (Box 42)
    - Paley Studio, Ltd., 1983-1994; (3 folders) (Box 42)
    - Travel Expenses, 1980-1985, undated (Box 42)
  - Audio-Visual Material (Box 42)
    - Audio Cassettes, 1983-1985, undated; (12 cassettes, 4 folders) (Box 42)
    - Darry, David D., Behind the Fence: Albert Paley, Metalsmith, (Reel, See Box 107)), 1976 (Box 42)
    - Video Tapes, 1980-1984; (6 folders) (Box 43)
    - Biographical Material, 1979-1990, undated; (3 folders) (Box 43)
  - Commissions (Box 44)
    - General, 1970-1991, undated; (12 folders) (Box 44)
    - Atlanta, Ga., Promenade Sculpture Project, 1981-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 44)
    - Bethesda, Md., Artery Organization [developers], 1982-1984, undated (Box 45)
    - Birmingham, Ala., 1983-1990, undated; (3 folders) (Box 45)
    - Chicago, Ill., 1981-1987, undated; (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Dallas, Tex., Dallas Providence Towers, 1983-1984, undated (Box 45)
    - Dallas, Tex., Dallas Zoo, 1985-1987 (Box 45)
    - Dallas, Tex., Fountain Place Criswell Development Company, 1983-1987, undated (Box 45)
    - Dallas, Tex., General, 1983-1988, undated (Box 45)
    - Hartford, Conn., 1984-1990, undated (Box 45)
    - Houston, Tex., Cullen Center, 1981-1983, undated (Box 45)
    - Houston, Tex., General, 1980-1988; (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Houston, Tex., Wortham Theater Center, 1981-1988, undated; (3 folders; See also: OV 111) (Box 45)
    - Houston, Tex., Wortham Theater Center, 1981-1988, undated; (3 folders) (Box 46)
    - Miami, Fla., 1981-1988, undated (Box 46)
    - Proposal Drawings, 1985-1986, undated (Box 46)
    - Naples, Fla., Naples Philharmonic Performing Arts Center (See also OV 111), 1988-1990, undated (Box 46)
    - New Orleans, La., 1983-1986, undated (Box 46)
    - New York, N.Y., Central Park Zoo, 1981-1989, undated (Box 46)
    - New York, N.Y., Lasdon Research Memorial Center, Cornell University Medical College, 1978-1988, undated; (2 folders; See also: OV 111) (Box 46)
    - New York, N.Y., 23rd Street Subway Station, Lexington Ave. Line, 1981-1989, undated (Box 46)
    - Orlando, Fla., Hyatt Regency Cypress Walk, 1983-1985 (Box 46)
    - Pawling, N.Y., Ziff Stafford Home, 1983-1988, undated (Box 46)
    - Philadelphia, Pa., 1982, 1984-1988, undated (Box 46)
    - Pittsburgh, Pa., 1982-1988, undated; (2 folders; See also: OV 111) (Box 46)
    - Richmond, Va., Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1982-1986, undated (Box 46)
    - Rochester, N.Y., Margaret Woodbury Strong Museum, 1981-1984, undated (Box 47)
    - Washington, D.C., Keyes, Condon & Florance Architects, 1988, undated (Box 47)
    - Washington, D.C., Marriott Flagship Hotel (See also: OV 111), 1982-1986, undated (Box 47)
    - Washington, D.C., National Zoological Park, Smithsonian Institution, 1983-1985, undated (Box 47)
    - Washington, D.C., Prospect Place Clock, Georgetown Court, 1980, 1984-1985, undated; (2 folders) (Box 47)
    - Washington, D.C., Washington Hebrew Congregation, 1987-1989, undated (Box 47)
    - Washington, D.C., Willard Building, 1982-1986, undated (Box 47)
    - Winston-Salem, No. Carolina, 1984-1988, undated (Box 47)
  - Concept Drawings and Miscellaneous Blueprints (See OV 112, OV 117, OV 118), 1979-1987, undated (Box 47)
  - Correspondence (Box 47)
    - Albert Paley Photographs, 1981-1988, undated; (3 folders) (Box 47)
    - Articles and Books on Paley, 1982-1989, undated; (2 folders) (Box 47)
    - Copyright Issues, 1983-1986, undated; (2 folders) (Box 47)
    - Film and Video, 1976-1988 (Box 48)
    - General, 1979-Sept. 1985 (Box 48)
    - General, Oct., 1985-1988; (13 folders) (Box 49)
    - General, 1989-2001, undated; (12 folders) (Box 50)
    - Museums, 1983-1985, undated (Box 50)
    - Other Galleries, 1982-1985, undated (Box 50)
    - Tallix Foundry, Peekskill, N.Y., 1980, 1982-1986, undated (Box 50)
  - Exhibitions (Box 50)
    - General, 1984-1996, undated (Box 50)
    - International, 1980-1989, undated (Box 50)
    - 1980, The Metalwork of Albert Paley (Box 50)
    - 1983, Albert Paley: The Iron Aesthetic, 1982-1986, undated (Box 50)
    - 1983, Orientalism, 1982-1984 (Box 50)
    - 1984, Ironworks: Albert Paley, 1977-1987, undated (Box 50)
    - 1985-1986, The Art of Metal, 1981-1986, undated; (5 folders) (Box 50)
    - 1988, Architectural Art: Affirming the Design Relationship, 1988, undated (Box 51)
    - 1989, Artful Objects: Recent American Crafts (Box 51)
    - 1991, Albert Paley: Sculptural Adornment, 1991-1992 (Box 51)
    - 1991, Recent Sculptures by Albert Paley (Box 51)
    - 1992, Albert Paley: Recent Work, 1988-1992 (Box 51)
    - 1994, Organic Logic (Box 51)
  - Foundries, 1982-1986, undated (Box 51)
  - Lists (Box 51)
    - Mailing, 1981-1991, undated; (4 folders) (Box 51)
    - Prices, 1988-1991, undated (Box 51)
    - Sales, 1985-1986, undated (Box 51)
  - Loan Agreements, 1981-1992, undated; (4 folders) (Box 51)
  - Notes (Box 51)
    - Lectures, 1986-1990. undated (Box 51)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981-1986, undated; (2 folders) (Box 51)
  - Photographs (Box 51)
    - Albert Paley, 1985, 1992, undated; (2 folders) (Box 51)
    - Architectural Screens, 1983 (Box 51)
    - Banisters and Railings, Clyde's Restaurant, Tysons Corner, Va., 1979-1981 (Box 51)
    - Benches and Tree Grates, Washington, D.C., 1981-1983, undated (Box 51)
    - Bridge Railings, Rochester, N.Y., 1989 (Box 51)
    - Candlesticks (See also Box 107, Albert Paley, Photographs, 1976, 1979, undated), 1977-1989 (Box 52)
    - Door Pulls and Sculpture, Willard Building, 1985-1986 (Box 52)
    - Albert Paley: Metal Sculpture, 1989 (Box 52)
    - The Art of Metal, 1978-1986, undated (Box 52)
    - Metalworks: The Art of Albert Paley, 1986 (Box 52)
    - Recent Sculpture by Albert Paley, 1980-1991; (2 folders) (Box 52)
    - Fence, Hunter Museum, Chattanooga, Tenn., 1974-1975, 1979 (Box 52)
    - Fireplace Ornaments, 1977-1984 (Box 52)
    - Fountain, Clyde's Restaurant, Tysons Corner, Va., 1983, undated (Box 52)
    - Gates (Box 52)
      - Albany Gates, Albany, N.Y., 1980-1985, undated (Box 52)
      - Central Park Zoo, New York, N.Y., 1982-1984, undated (Box 52)
      - Marriott Hotel, Washington, D.C., 1983 (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous (See also Box 107 sol), 1976-1983, undated (Box 52)
      - Private Residence, Washington, D.C., 1976-1982 (Box 52)
      - Renwick Gallery, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1974, 1977 (Box 52)
      - Rose Garden, N.Y. [upstate], 1976-1990, undated (Box 52)
      - Victoria and Albert Museum, London, England, 1982 (Box 52)
      - Virginia Museum of Art, Richmond, Va., 1985 (Box 52)
    - Lectern, Megatrends, Inc., Washington, D.C., 1974-1987 (Box 52)
    - Menorahs, Washington Hebrew Congregation, Washington, D.C., 1988 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous (See also Box 107, sol), 1975-1987, undated (Box 52)
    - Plant Stands, 1979-1987, undated (Box 52)
    - Sculpture (Box 52)
      - Animal Sculpture, 1985 (Box 52)
      - Margaret Woodbury Strong Museum, Rochester, N.Y., 1982 (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous, 1974-1991; (2 folders) (Box 52)
      - New York Governor's Award, 1986 (Box 52)
      - Wortham Center, Houston, Texas, 1987 (Box 52)
    - Tables, 1977-1987; (2 folders) (Box 52)
  - Posters (See OV 113), 1986, undated (Box 53)
  - Printed Material, 1977-2001, undated; (13 folders; See also Box 107, sol) (Box 53)
  - Project Drawings and Documentation, 1977-1988, undated (Box 54)
  - Proofs for Albert Paley: Sculpture catalog (See Box 107, sol), 1989 (Box 54)
  - Writings about Albert Paley (Box 54)
    - Fendrick, Daniel, Unpublished Manuscripts and Notes, 1935, 1970-1986, undated; (4 folders) (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, 1977-1995, undated; (2 folders) (Box 54)
  - Oversized, Darry, David D., Behind the Fence: Albert Paley, Metalsmith (Motion Picture Reel) (Box 107 (sol))
  - Oversized, Photographs, 1976, 1979, undated (Box 107 (sol))
  - Oversized, Printed Material, 1984 (Box 107 (sol))
  - Oversized, Proofs of Albert Paley: Sculpture Catalog, 1989 (Box 107 (sol))
  - Oversized, Houston Wortham Theater Center, 1987 (Box OV 111)
  - Oversized, Naples Philharmonic Performing Arts Center, Blueprints, 1988 (Box OV 111)
  - Oversized, Lasdon Research Memorial Center, Cornell University Medical College Blueprints, 1988 (Box OV 111)
  - Oversized, Pittsburgh, Poster Case, Blueprints, undated (Box OV 111)
  - Oversized, Washington, D.C., Marriott Flagship Hotel, Blueprints, 1983, undated (Box OV 111)
  - Oversized, Albert Paley, Concept Drawings and Miscellaneous Blueprints, 1979-1987, undated (Box OV 112)
  - Oversized, Albert Paley, Concept Drawings and Miscellaneous Blueprints, 1979-1987, undated (Box OV 117)
  - Oversized, Albert Paley, Concept Drawings and Miscellaneous Blueprints, 1979-1987, undated (Box OV 118)
  - Oversized, Albert Paley Posters, 1986, undated (Box OV 113)
- Commissioned Works and Projects, 1972-2000, undated; Series 3; (Boxes 54-57; 3.5 linear feet)
  The files within this series document both successful and unsuccessful commission applications and projects arranged by the gallery on behalf of various artists. The series is arranged alphabetically by name of project or by the name of the artist.
  - Art in Public Places Proposals (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous Artists, 1982-1992, undated (Box 54)
    - Paley, Albert, 1982-1991, undated (Box 54)
  - Art Sources, Inc., Projects, Miami Beach, Florida, 1985-1995, undated (Box 54)
  - Artists' Approval Forms, 1980-1986 (Box 54)
  - Artists for Architecture, 1990 (Box 54)
  - Atlanta 1996, Atlanta Committee for the Olympic Games, Atlanta, Ga., 1988-1994, undated (Box 54)
  - Birmingham Civil Rights District Project, City of Birmingham, Birmingham, Ala., 1990-1992; (3 folders) (Box 54)
  - Broward County Art in Public Places Project, Fort Lauderdale, Fla., 1986-1990, undated (Box 54)
  - Cleveland Gateway Project, Committee for Public Art, Cleveland, Ohio, 1992 (Box 54)
  - Colorado Springs Airport, Airport Art Committee, Colorado Springs, Colo., 1993 (Box 54)
  - Dallas Federal Reserve Bank Project, Federal Reserve Board, Washington, D.C., 1992 (Box 54)
  - "Dead" Commissions, 1984-1991; (2 folders) (Box 54)
  - Denver Public Library, Denver Public Art Program, Denver, Colo., 1990-1993, undated (Box 54)
  - Downtown Seattle Transit Project, Municipality of Metropolitan Seattle, Seattle, Wash., 1985-1986 (Box 55)
  - Freddie Mac/Architectural Interiors, 1990 (Box 55)
  - Hakone Open Air Museum, Tokyo, Japan, 1992 (Box 55)
  - Hechinger Corporation Art Collection, Landover, Md., 1984-1989 (Box 55)
  - Hechinger Corporation Art Collection, Landover, Md., Jan.-Jun. 1990 (Box 55)
  - Hechinger Corporation Art Collection, Landover, Md., Jul.-Jan. 1990, 1991-circa 1995 (Box 55)
  - Hechinger Corporation Art Collection, Landover, Md., undated (Box 55)
  - Hellmuth, Obata, and Kassabaum, Washington, D.C., 1991-1992 (Box 55)
  - International Sculpture Center, Washington, D.C., 1986-1992 (Box 55)
  - Japanese Projects (Box 55)
    - 1992 Yokohama Art Fair, 1987-1992, undated; (2 folders) (Box 55)
    - Yokohama Museum of Art, 1972-1991, undated; (4 folders) (Box 55)
  - Marriott Corporation, Washington, D.C., 1988-1990 (Box 55)
  - Metro Center Public Art Project, Oliver T. Carr Company, Washington, D.C., 1990 (Box 55)
  - Metro-Dade Art in Public Places Project, Miami, Fla., 1978-1996, undated (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous Commission Proposals, 1979-2000; (3 folders) (Box 55)
  - New Denver International Airport Art Program, Stapleton International Airport, Denver, Colo., (Gilliam, Paley), 1992 (Box 55)
  - Nicollet Mall, Public Arts Program, Minneapolis, Minn., 1989-1990 (Box 55)
  - Paley, Albert (Box 56)
    - Arizona State University, Phoenix, Ariz., 1989-1991; (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - Birmingham Museum of Art, Birmingham, Ala., 1989 (Box 56)
    - C & B Bank Bldg., Charleston, S.C., 1989-1990 (Box 56)
    - California Prospects, 1982-1985 (Box 56)
    - Central Park Zoo Archway Project, Central Park Conservancy, New York, N.Y., 1983-1986 (Box 56)
    - Clyde's of Tyson's Corner Restaurant, Vienna, Va., 1979 (Box 56)
    - Coliseum Project, Charlotte-Mecklenberg Arts Commission, Charlotte, N.C., 1988-1989 (Box 56)
    - Fine Arts Museum of the South at Mobile, Mobile, Ala., 1988-1989 (Box 56)
    - Fireplace Fenders for E. Joseph House, Hampton, Va., 1989-1990 (Box 56)